solar-aid.org 2019-06-29

# Privacy Policy - SolarAid

## **SolarAid Privacy Policy**

### Principles

We believe in inspiring people who believe in what we believe to help spread our mission story. Our privacy policy explains how we use and protect and hold any personal information about you by applying this principle.

### Who we are

SolarAid is a UK charity registered number 1115960. We also own a social enterprise SunnyMoney Ltd.

### What information do we collect about you?

We collect information about you when you make a donation, purchase an item, such as a solar light or sign up to our newsletter. This can consist of information such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone or mobile number, bank account details and whether you are a taxpayer.

We also collect information when you choose to complete supporter surveys, provide feedback, sign up to an event, including fundraising for us.

### How we will use the information about you?

We collect information about you to correctly process your donation, help us raise funds, send you information that you may choose to share, and support you if you choose to fundraise or advocate for us for our mission.

We seek feedback and data to understand why people support us, what we can do to attract more people like you, and how we can inspire and help you spread our story.

We may need to contact you for administration purposes such as your tax status, or to help complete a transaction.

We also collect information from our website to improve your experience when you visit it and monitor which pages are visited the most often.

### Will you be contacted for marketing purposes?

SolarAid will contact you for the marketing purpose of communicating our mission and how you can help where you have opted in by email and/or post. We may also contact you if there is reasonable expectation on your part for us to do so, for example to thank you,  _and_ you have not opted out of being contacted. You can always request to opt out of further communications at any time.

### Access to your information and correcting it

Accuracy of your information is important to us. You may ask us to correct or remove any information you think is inaccurate.

You can opt out of emails we send anytime by clicking unsubscribe. When we contact you by post you will be given the option to opt out of future mailings.

If you would like to change how we communicate with you, or update information about you or receive a copy of the information we hold about you please contact us.

### Cookies – information we collect from your computer or mobile device

We use cookies, which are small text files that are downloaded onto your PC. The next time you visit that site, your PC checks to see if it has a cookie that is relevant (that is, one containing the site name) and sends the information contained in that cookie back to the site. They are useful as they allow a website to recognise a user’s device or browser and whether you have visited the site before.

We use cookies to identify which parts of our website people are visiting. Information supplied in cookies also helps us measure our online marketing to attract more support for our mission.

### Other websites

The SolarAid website contains links to other websites and these will have their own policies which may change so we can’t accept responsibility or liability of the privacy practice of such websites.

### Changes

Updates to our privacy policy will be made on this web page. This privacy policy was last updated on 11th April 2018.

### How to contact us

Please contact us if you have any questions about our privacy policy or information we hold about you.

  * Email [info@solar-aid.org](mailto:info@solar-aid.org)
  * Write to us at The Information Officer, SolarAid, [30-36 Pritchard’s Rd, London E2 9AP, UK](https://www.google.co.uk/maps/dir//solaraid/data=!4m6!4m5!1m1!4e2!1m2!1m1!1s0x48761b4307170413:0x6199d5e125943c76?sa=X&ved=2ahUKEwiGiPa1qvfdAhVQTcAKHaxkDuYQ9RcwJHoECAQQFQ)
  * Call us on +44 (0)207 278 0400
